CHRIS OLSEN

github.com/chrisolsen chris@chrisolsen.org +1 780-887-2008

WHY HIRE ME?

I have more than **15** years of experience in creating applications from concept to completion...the only way you can do it for this long is if you love what you do. I love it because learning new things is a requirement, and allows one to improve themselves everyday.

WORK HISTORY

Sr. Software Developer 09/2020 to current

Government of Alberta Edmonton

Typescript React Svelte Angular Jest Storybook

- · Responsible for initiating the creation of the UI team
- Primary developer for the <u>UI Component</u> library for dev teams within the provincial government.
- Designed and developed core services made available to other teams.

Sr. Software Developer 12/2018 to 07/2020

CenturyLink Edmonton

Java Spring Boot AngularJS Python Cypress Docker MongoDB

- Helped to add disaster recovery functionality allowing for system recovery to CenturyLink, AWS or Azure cloud instances.
- Worked on Cloud Application Manager analytics backend and rewrote the testing component to allow for faster and selective testing.

Software Developer (1 year contract) 07/2017 to 08/2018 **Alberta College of Pharmacists** Edmonton

Elm Node.js AngularJS ServiceNow MSSQL

- Identified and fixed application usability and security deficiencies.
- Created UI designs for next version of the application.
- Developed Elm application to export ServiceNow data to Quickbooks .iif format.
- Implemented data migration CLI that optimized existing migration times to ServiceNow from over 5 hours to a few minutes.
- Created Elm application to convert old quickbook data type to csv files

Software Developer (1 month contract) 07/2017 to 08/2017

Ledcor Edmonton

AngularJS Gulp

- Created a deployment system that decreased deployment time from 10 minutes to a few seconds.
- Reduced total application size by ~90%.

Sr. Software Developer 04/2014 to 05/2016

Showbie Edmonton

Ember JS Go

- Developed web application replicating the existing iOS application for the web.
- Created web application which allowed school districts to manage teacher licenses.
- Built Go utility to convert .po files supplied by the translating service to the custom locale format required for Android, web and iOS.

Software Developer | Architect 2011 to 2012

Mitremedia Edmonton

Ruby on Rails Nginx MySql PHP

- Optimized web applications created by bought-out companies (reduced response times from > 2min to less than 5 seconds).
- Server and deployment setup for existing applications.

Android Developer | Architect 2010 to 2011

Drivewyze Edmonton

Java Android Sglite3

- · Promoted to Architect after less than a year.
- Designed and developed Android application allowing semi drivers to receive bypass notifications from weigh stations.
- Responsible for creating and documenting logic for mobile devices and backend API.
- UI design for all mobile platforms

Full-stack Developer 2010

Minigroup Calgary

Ruby on Rails jQuery MySql

- Worked on the backend server logic and frontend jQuery
- Created search module to allow users to find notes, links and/or assets

Web Developer (contract) 2008 to 2010

Zedi Edmonton

jQuery ASP.NET Oracle

- Successfully completed a scalability project which gave the site the ability to handle increased user load.
- Completed the SCADA drag n' drop interface that provided users that ability to monitor various on-site sensors.

System Analyst II 2005-2007

Alberta Education Edmonton

ASP.NET VB.NET MSSQL

• Created web application that allowed special requests to be made and processed online.

Software Developer (4 month internship) 2005

Alberta Education Edmonton

VB.NET Win32 MSSQL

- Developed in-house application that allowed flagged exams with scan errors and allowed them to be corrected online instead of manually.
- Increased the speed of the process scan errors more than 100 times.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Woddy

Workout of the day app tracker. Elm, Go, AppEngine

MathOps

Allows kids to practice their basic math skills and track their progress over time. Android

LeagueSmart

Created game schedules and provided score/stat entry. RubyOnRails, MySql

Onlinelisting

Allowed real-estate agents to create personal sites. RubyOnRails, MySql

EDUCATION

- Udacity Intro to Self Driving Cars
- Udacity Android Developer Nanodegree
- Northern Alberta Institute of Technology
- University of Alberta: BSc Chemistry with Specialization

SKILLS

Typescript Go Elixir Svelte React Elm Phoenix MySql PostgreSql